VICTOR GODWIN

FULLSTACK DEVELOPER

No 152 Gado Nasko Way, Kubwa FCT - Abuja +234 (706) 789-1458 Victoranimate556@gmail.com

EXPERIENCE

Namely, New York City - USA, — Data Engineer

(Andela's partnering company)

March 2018 - PRESENT

Building Data pipelines, ETL processes, Data analysis, Data query optimization, Building Data schemas, Creation of design docs, Code reviews, Data workflow.

Andela, Lagos - Nigeria — Software Developer

April 2019 - Present

Work effectively with design teams to ensure software solutions elevate client-side experience, Modify existing software to fix bugs, upgrade interfaces and improve performance, build elegant web and mobile apps.

Hepzi Global Surf, KANO — Technical Director

January 2013 - Present

Develop curriculums for tech classes, Network administration, Software maintenance, Business report and analysis, HR executive.

EDUCATION

Ebonyi State University, Nigeria — *B.Sc Mathematics*

January 2003 - August 2007

Class Rep 2006, Students' Academic Director 2005, Final Year Coordinator 2007.

SUMMARY

I have ample experience in software development with interests in web and mobile applications, project management and data engineering. I am also passionate about code mentoring; grooming students into world-class developers. I believe in excellence, passion, integrity and collaboration.

SKILLS

Agile Methodologies, Version Control, Project Management, Communication, Remote teamwork, Database management, Data analysis, Mobile app development (React Native), Online coaching/ mentorship, TDD.

STACKS

Javascript, SQL, React, REST Api, Graphql, Nodejs, Mongo DB, Git, Postgres,

Ecwa Secondary School, Nigeria — SSCE

August 2002 - June 2007

Deputy Senior Prefect, President - Anglican Students Association of Nigeria.

PROJECTS

WeVote — Citizen Mobilisation App http://wevote-ng.herokuapp.com/

AutoMart App

Andela Boothcamp Project

Frontend - https://cstudio7.github.io/Automart/Backend -

Video Streaming with Twitch

Web crawlina

https://codepen.io/obinnaeye/full/EypJBy/

Global Meteorite Landings

Data Visualisation with D3

https://codepen.io/obinnaeye/full/PbBWmM/

Doping in Professional Bicycle Racing

Data Visualisation with D3

https://codepen.io/obinnaeye/full/PbErBQ/

Monthly Global Land-Surface Temperature

Data Visualisation with D3

https://codepen.io/obinnaeye/full/XNZpZL/

Game of Life

Effects of overcrowding vs loneliness on life

https://codepen.io/obinnaeye/full/xEJzao/

Tic-Tac-Toe Game

Algorithm Exercise

https://codepen.io/obinnaeye/full/ozjWgV/

Digital Calculator

Application of Javascript in general sciences

https://codepen.io/obinnaeye/full/Vjoqzj/

Simon Game

Memory exercise

https://codepen.io/obinnaeye/full/mAPxjW/

AWARDS

Saucecode Pioneer Winners

Team WeVote: We built a citizen mobilisation app for

Nigerian elections.

http://wevote-ng.herokuapp.com/

LANGUAGES

Igbo, English, Hausa

HOBBIES

Playing guitar (Bass guitar)
Playing table tennis
Learning new stuffs
Talking to young people

LINKS

https://about.me/nnenanya, https://ng.linkedin.com/in/ki ngobi, https://github.com/obinnaeye